Anubhav Sharma

Dallas, TX, +1(682)-360-3066

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/anubhavsharma26/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Results-driven SDET professional with 8+ years in automation & strong communication.

SKILLS

Testing Tools/Skills	Selenium (IDE, WebDriver), Eclipse, Maven, RESTful APIs Automation
Programming:	Python, Java, SQL
Skills:	Reporting/Testing Tools: Quality Center, Rally, JIRA, TestNG, Selenium, Postman, PyTest
	Frameworks: Spring Boot, Django
	Database: NO SQL, Mongo DB, SQLite, Apache Spark, Redis
	DevOps: GitHub, Jenkins, source control management, Agile
Certifications:	Automation: Google IT Automation, TOSCA Certificated.
	Cloud: Google Cloud Fundamentals, Azure Fundamentals; AWS Cloud Technical Essentials
	DevOps: DevOps on AWS
Certifications:	Automation: Google IT Automation, TOSCA Certificated. Cloud: Google Cloud Fundamentals, Azure Fundamentals; AWS Cloud Technical Essentials

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Altimetrik, US 2023 – Present

LPL Financial – Senior Software Development in Test

- Designed and executed comprehensive test automation for the newly **implemented Advisor Base Pricing** system at LPL Financial, a critical component of their fee billing process.
- Designed and testing Automation in SQL Blackbird framework and achieved 100% coverage identifying and resolving 10 critical defects before production rollout.
- Led and actively participated in Agile Scrum ceremonies, including PI Planning, Sprint Planning, Daily Standups, Defect Review, Sprint Demo, and Retrospectives.
- Demonstrated ability to write complex queries for data validation using SQL.
- Coached fellow team members on best practices and actively contributed to continuous improvement initiatives.
- Demonstrated programming/development experience in languages such as Java, Python, coupled with expertise in automation frameworks like Selenium, and TestNG.
- Possessed strong problem-solving skills, resourcefulness, and determination in a fast-paced Agile environment.
- Implemented a data-driven **API testing approach** using Excel data files, enabling efficient test execution across multiple test cases.
- Currently working with API modernization team TIBCO to AWS, Identified and reported 5 critical API defects during testing, preventing potential production issues.

University of Texas, Arlington, US

August 2021 – December 2022

Email:asharma.careers@gmail.com

Portfolio

Role – Database System Teaching Assistant

Accenture November 2014 – December 2020

Role - Software Test Automation Specialist

- Hands on experience for test automation projects building and maintain Salesforce Automation.
- Developed **web dashboards and tools** to speed up automation and reduce repetitive tasks (Tech used: ReactJS, VueJS, Django, Bootstrap, Chatbot, Apache Spark etc).
- Designed and developed **10+ hybrid framework** including Cucumber which included functionalities likes data driven, one touch execute/scheduled execution, auto email trigger, prediction of any risk with available defects.
- Accenture **Green Field Trainer** (**SME**) for test automation (REST APIs and Selenium) to new joiners.

EDUCATION